so now we're live so welcome ishvan
uh someone who has been to the village
in kenya called j10
and i'm just going to find out a little
bit more about your experience with them
and how how that went so how did you
first
find out about j-10 and get involved
yeah okay first of all
let me tell you that
i'm okay
can can we can you switch off the life
please
i want to tell you something
i can't switch off the live sorry now
that we're live i can't switch it off
otherwise we won't be able to do it
we'd have to do a whole other whole
other one
okay so the problem is
that we don't like to
show ourselves
we are not showing
our good deeds we are not showing our
faith
so this is the problem if it's only my
voice
then it is okay but
uh because as i told you
uh we are we are one to work
in the back we are not something that
like you know
like a business we are done doing
marketing
we are done doing anything like this so
let me ask that uh who who say
this life or is it for you the idea is
to put it out to the j-10 community to
get the
to get the um somebody's story who's
actually physically been there without
using
their data right without i want to
interview them as well people who live
at j10
but to be able to say like put real
faces and real voices
to that story right so it is imperative
that it's like a real face and a real
voice i get what you're saying
your faith and stuff is about doing it
for the deed and not about doing it for
the recognition but this is about giving
j10 recognition
right so using some of your credibility
just that you're a human who's been
there
to to bring to bring voice to that
okay okay so what uh i can tell you
that i went there
a bike by the work way
this is a web page which is
collecting the the volunteer
opportunities
so uh through this work away
website uh i went to kenya
uh but the point is that what is the
situation in kenya now
this is the point and the point is that
is not that what
we done before because i don't want to
share that
because it's a i i will tell you
when we are personally but
we want to keep it in in
you know as i told you we don't publish
okay we try to keep it in in in secret
so the point is that at the moment
because of this covet situation
and because of the dryness
uh in kenya and
in the ethan village uh in joseph
house is close to kisumu
this homa bay country in kenya
it's very hard situation at the moment
because of the dryness and because of
the covet
these two things now came together
and that's why they are suffering
there are a huge
cue to get the waters
for example because
there is no water in the river
and in the small rivers in this season
and it can last one or two months
we don't know when the rain is coming
so that is the most important thing that
the life is very hard now
in in houma bay
in kenya uh so the people are walking
uh five to ten kilometers to get the
water
and still there is a line
at the wheel and you still need to pay
for the water
they don't have money to build a wheel
they tried it they tried it manually
not by machine
but it is very difficult because
you have to go down 15 meter
and it is a rock
it's full with rocks stones
even uh 10 meter you go down is still
stones there
so it is very very difficult to do it
manually
and the machine is very expensive
so that's why is the situation is not
easy
so that's why we decided to help them
and is not me
is there is a foundation and
basically it's god who helped them
through the foundation
we adapted some
water tanks for them
and this water tank they can keep the
water
the rain water they can collect it
and they can use it
for watering
the vegetables or for drinking
if you don't have anything else and
the next step we would like to do
this house to build a house
for the mo for the most miserable
children
for those children who are
who have a difficult time in the family
and difficult life
to to live in this house so
so this is this is a situation in in
kenya
basically this is the thank you for
sharing that can i ask i just
also wanted to know so that the viewers
get a bit of an idea
when you were there time wise and how
long you were there for
yeah let me think
because we have some mission last year i
was
there i think it was like 2090
yeah yeah i think so yeah yeah and so
that's when you guys put in the water
tanks
sorry that's when you put in the water
yes yes yes that was
we put some water tanks
so yeah in march it was in march
i spent two months in africa one month
in ethiopia mamas in kenya
so how long were you how long were you
at the j-10 village for
at joseph place i was i think two weeks
time
okay and what can you share a bit about
your experience maybe uh meeting the
there because there are children who
live there right he has children and
then there's the
yeah very miserable condition
very miserably condition you cannot tell
it by words
you cannot tell it by words
so
[Music]
it is a you know
i i do believe that we really need to
help
because uh you know this lack of water
it it causes a lot of problem
and this is this is the main problem the
the less water
yeah no water is the key to life so what
is the
solution i haven't looked into the water
situation as far as like what is
something that would bring
them water where they don't have to
necessarily attract is it just that they
need the money so they can track the
the long distance q and pay for it
that is how we get them through the year
or
yeah okay
the shortly uh solution
is to support them
month by month
to help for the most miserable
widows and orphans
because there is also a lot of videos
who are living alone a lot of people
have
hiv many
many and that's why
uh there are half orphans orphans
or or or both the parents are died
so the the short
solution is the monthly uh helping
for these people it is it is maybe 10
family
around the village and
the long solution is
either this water tanks
or to to make another
uh wheel well
to me how much they would need to make a
well how much money that would be
yeah that is the problem that
the world is very expensive uh
what the wealth they have
that was
let me think
around
fifty thousand dollar
oh wow but that well is with a solar
with a solar engine so not a simple well
that's a full system uh
with the solar engine they can get
the energy and the water can come up and
that is a very deep well
that's the israel project was that was
the israel project
and yeah to build
an a normal well just uh
to drawing and well it's around
let me think
uh something like uh eight
uh thousand dollar
eight thousand dollar that that's
just to drill the well and
and and maybe make
[Music]
have you say in english the top
so that's still expensive
yeah that's why we we decided the water
tank because it's cheaper
the water tank it's around the
you can get 200 from two hundred dollars
you can get water tanks to three hundred
dollars
do you know how big the water tanks are
size wise
how big are the water tanks i mean i'm
picturing really huge are we talking
the the um smaller it depends
it depends it's 3 000 liter
uh 3000 liters here
and how many did you guys put in of
these
water tanks i think we adapt around four
four of them all right is there anything
else you want to say before we
um stop recording so that this interview
isn't is it
too long so hopefully people watch it
and can can donate money to
joseph in the j-10 village
yeah the main the only thing that i want
to say that
please be sensitive
i was there and i saw the situation
uh you know they
they can survive very difficult
very difficult but they can survive
because they adapt the situation
so it is basically not about them
it is about us
it is an opportunity for us
to open our heart
this is a let me say this is a test for
us
do we open our heart or we keep it close
so please open your heart even for the
satan village
or anyone else you can see
suffering people in africa or even
around you
please open your heart this is my